[Music]
the Hyundai ionic 5 and Hyundai exra are
amongst the best of 2023 joining me
today to accept the award is Mr tarun
gar Chief oper tring officer Hyundai
Motor India tarun welcome thank you for
joining us thank you so much so you've
got two beautiful cars that you've
brought us today which one is more
important to you no actually both have a
very important role uh Frankly Speaking
when we launched the ionic 5 this is a
big statement because it was so well
awarded and it was kind of far ahead of
the of the times you know and frankly
when we launched it we were kind of
thinking okay uh whether we'll sell 300
whether we'll sell 500 in the year and
I'm so happy to see that now we have
sold more than 950 Vehicles already and
it has it has been a big change in the
way people looked at electric cars you
know the kind of clientele we have all
of them have most of them have have been
driving a luxury car and when they see
iic 5 they see that oh my God it has
features which are even more than say a
luxury car so it has really given given
us that kind of a filp to our electric
vehicle plans and of course we are very
encouraged and you would have seen that
we already announced that we going to do
a localization of battery packs and
which will really help us to bring more
and more electric cars so I think this
is a big big big movement for hindai
India so how do you do the balancing act
in terms of brand positioning because
like you said uh this is at the higher
end of the spectrum uh that is more
volumes and yet you have to manage sort
of brand expectations at both ends of
the market so how do you balance that I
think that's a that's a tricky one uh
but uh you would know that you know uh
if you see every company you know it's
always about sustainability of the brand
at the same time you need uh you need to
really live and for that you need
volumes you need market share you need
profits so I think uh as long as you do
the right things we have always believed
that we'll arrive at the right place so
you don't run after the results Frankly
Speaking the extra uh you know we
thought that we'll have we'll have some
really really new benchmarks so six
airbags a standard was something we
discuss at length okay this is a car
which is say less than 10 lakh range
will the customer be open to this you
know because it leads to increase cost
but I'm telling you this became one of
the one of the key features which really
gave a very big filp to the extra sales
so much so that now more than 60% of my
sales are coming from SUVs so uh so you
know sometimes you have to take a call
and the important thing is what our
belief has always been do
you you know uh will you bring a new
Benchmark in the segment that is what we
have tried to do right from the time we
we had the Centro in 1998 and till our
latest car extra we have always tried to
raise the Benchmark so you mentioned six
airbags as being a differentiating
factor and something that has drawn in
people we we always talk about safety
but uh is safety now a point of priority
in the minds of customers to the extent
where they base their buying decisions
absolutely I mean you won't believe it
you know uh as you know from 1 October
all our cars across models and variants
are now equipped with six airbags and
the customers are so happy about it uh
and the dealers are saying that the
traffic has increased uh we having a
good uh you know we had a very good
navratras we are really building on to a
very good Tas as well the whole idea is
because customer is really really much
more careful about all the members in
the family earlier I think uh while we
always loved the families but I think
what a big change which has happened
especially in the co is that we are want
to really take even more care about all
the members not only the person who is
driving that is really helped plus the
five star rating on the like on the
Verna I mean it has been received really
really very well by the customers I
think safety as a key buying factor is
only gaining importance and going
forward I believe it will be a key
differentiating factor in customers
purchase decision that's good to hear
yes um other than from a safety
standpoint what are the other standout
things that you're hearing as feedback
from customers of the extra look uh
people are really wanting uh uh you know
77% of the customers wanted a sunroof
now this is shows very very clearly that
how everybody is aspirational because
sunroof I think is much more about
aspiration than functionality so this is
something people have really really
loved the dash cam because as you know
the customer is getting younger and they
want to really capture all the moments
in addition to the security features so
the dash cam is really gaining a lot of
popularity uh and of course it the extra
is so much more than a car because it is
it is an SUV and this khaki green color
35% of my extra sales are in khaki green
color believe you me otherwise it's all
about white but here you know a big
statement has been made and people are
sending us videos of what all they're
doing with the car of course we had a
very good tagline think outside think
exter we had a new brand ambassador in
hardik Panda I think it really really
panned out beautifully for us and here
we are sitting today I think we have
already received close to 9 5,000
bookings for the extra and it has really
proved to be a big Blockbuster for us so
I think hyai as a brand was very early
to recognize the aspirational sort of
needs of the Indian customer uh and I
think that's been key to to the success
of the brand over the last decade or so
or even more but how have you seen the
Indian customers aspirations change in
the last let's say decade or so
amazingly amazingly in fact if you
remember 2015 when CR was launched SUVs
used to contribute 133% to the indust
industry sales and today you see they
have already reached 49% like I
mentioned Hundai is already at 60% so we
have always believed in creating the
market you know that that shows a very
growth mindset because otherwise you
know suppose you have a market then
you'll say okay my market share is 15%
let me Target 15% that will limit you
but the moment you see okay there's an
open space there's something called a
demand there's something called a you
know something which the customer is not
really stating unstated demand I think
those are where the real real value
pools are there and this is what we have
always tried to do you talked about the
customer aspirations changing uh I mean
today I think style design of uh you
know uh features have become much more
important convenience has become much
more important people are going for Blue
Link connectivity 33% of my cars sold
are with Blue Link so people want
connected car sunroof I already
mentioned I mean even in the extra 77%
uh people want ventilated seats so uh
and of course six airbag as standard in
terms of safety I think going forward if
I see my career over the last 30 years
you know it was all about fuel
efficiency it was all about price it was
about functionality I think now it is
all about whether I see the car as an
extension of myself whether I see the
car it will give me protection not only
for myself for my family and it will it
will help me believe that yes I have
arrived in life I think those are the
factor which are really driving car
sales much more than before so talking
about aspiration and Enthusiast you have
the endline range of of cars what about
a proper end model when are we getting a
proper end model yeah yeah I know this
question was uh was coming and uh
frankly we are very very encouraged by
the global acceptance of the of the n
and uh in fact yesterday one of the
journalist colleagues was he you know he
tweeted about the the the the endline in
the electric car as well and we very
proud that we have been able to make a
niche and uh really gives uh gives us to
really get into the consideration set of
people who really love their cars they
want to really have that kind of a
thrill and the passion so Frankly
Speaking we are always uh you know open
to uh uh seeing that what is the right
time so the products are always there
but we just wait for the right time
because you need to have uh confidence
that you will have a sustainable volume
I think that's very very important and
then of course there's always that value
angle which always comes in when
whenever a product is to be launched in
India so as of now I would say that
there's no concrete plan uh but we very
encouraged by the kind of communication
we receive from the customers about the
N brand that how enthused they are and I
think this big transformation now that
from a ICN brand to a e EVN brand I
think this is a big change because EES
were always thought of you know as of
course Frugal and good for the
environment but as a performance car E I
think this is again a very big step up
from Hyundai and I'm very very proud to
be a part of this uh organization so in
terms of this EV road map you've seen a
lot of success of course with the ionic
and it's a phenomenal machine um but a
lot of or some Global manufacturers have
set out aggressive road maps and then
maybe starting to backtrack a little bit
from it U you're seeing demand but is it
the kind of volume demand that you
expect like how does that road map play
out I think this is very very tricky and
very very sensitive and yes last one
month if you see all the AR Les you know
so they are very very mixed but you see
the commitment and the direction as far
as H is concerned we have already
announced that we're going to invest
20,000 crores uh and most of it will be
towards the localization of battery
packs because if we want Mass adoption
of EVS the cost have to come down and
one critical components is of course the
battery packs so I think we are very
very committed uh to this cause and we
already announced a very aggressive plan
going forward look when such a big
transformation is happening I don't
think it's always like a like this I
think it will always be like this and
this the whole idea is to not lose focus
and the direction should be right you
keep on investing the moment you start
getting into the ROI game I think then
you lose focus so these are some things
which are we have to do something you
know so that we can create a Greener
cleaner environment for our next
Generations and I think there's a much
larger cause here so while yes uh today
I was reading about a global
manufacturer they Revis their their
volumes downwards but I don't we should
I don't think we should really read too
much into it because the direction is
right and you and if you see from the
base it's still a much higher number so
we have to look for positives we have to
look for things which can keep us going
rather than things which can which can
pull us back so we and and my one of my
favorite statements is sustainability is
never self- sustainable you need to
really invest in sustainability to make
it sustainable I think all of us as a
team and I'm very happy to see that all
the oems in India in fact the the race
towards EVS has really really
accelerated much faster than uh you know
what even we had anticipated so uh so I
think all of us will take uh this route
and it will have bumps but uh but I as
long as we're together as long as we are
focused as long as we are not really too
much into the ROI game I think we will
will reach the right place I think
that's a very good line sustainability
is not self- sustainable I'm going to
remember that thank you so finally
looking at 2024 there's a lot of global
geopolitical volatility potential
uncertainty going into uh next year how
do you see that playing out look I think
there are definitely concerns and but I
would say one thing that whenever we try
to forecast we we tend to be always very
conservative you should remember in Co
we had all predicted a doom and we saw
good growth even at the beginning of 23
when we were all trying to in fact I was
in a CM meeting and we trying to
forecast the growth and we said okay
maybe 3 and a half to 5% at best 6% and
here we are already January to October
we are at much more than 8 and a half 9%
maybe we'll end this year at an industry
at about 7 and a half% so India has
shown a lot of resilience uh the
concerns of course are increasing in
terms of geopolitical situation because
we never expected the war should would
would go on for such a long time so
there are challenges uh but we have to
uh see also that the base is also going
up 22 was the highest ever car industry
23 on top of it has will see a growth of
7 and a half% so I think even if even if
the growth moderates to say uh say low
single digits I don't think we should
really be too much Disturbed and even if
let me give you one more data uh base of
22 if you see Last 5 Years cagr it is in
the range of 3 and a half% even if you
say last 10 years cagr even that is in
the range of 3 and a half% so I don't
think that we can say that okay unless
we grow by 8 or 9% we have done very bad
I don't think so I think India as a
country is doing much better than how
the how the especially in the car market
as compared to the global economy me we
a young population car penetration is
still low I I see I continuously I'm
very happy about the the GST collections
so there are a lot of positive I already
talked about how the aspiration is
taking over functionality so uh yes 24
would have its challenges but I think we
we should be able to have our head above
the water that's a very positive to not
to end on thank you so much and thank
you for bringing us such impressive
machines every time thank you so much
and thank you for having me at the auto
X thank you thank
[Music]
you
n